utp.edu.my 2014-12-03

# Privacy Notice

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS(hereinafter referred to as “UTP”, “our”, “us” or “we”) wish to inform you that we take your privacy seriously and are committed in protecting it by maintaining the integrity and confidentiality of your personal data.  
  
This notice is served to help you understand the types of personal data we collect, how we use your personal data, with whom do we share your personal data with and how we protect your personal data.  
  
 **  
Types of Personal Data We Collect  
** **  
**The types of personal data that we collect may include your name, age, date of birth, place of birth, gender, marital status, particulars of parents and/or family members, passport/ID number, contact number, e-mail address, home address, telephone number, academic qualifications, nationality and health information.  
  
How We Use Your Personal Data The Purposes for which your personal data may be used include, but not limited to :-

  * For application as a student
  * For those who have been accepted as UTP student, your personal data will be used for the purpose of your studies
  * For application as an employee
  * For those who have been accepted as an employee, your personal data will be used for the purpose of your employment
  * For research purposes
  * For administration purposes
  * For alumni matters
  * For the purposes of fulfilling our contractual obligations
  * For the purposes of communicating with you
  * For the purposes of responding to your enquiries
  * For marketing purposes and/or to promote offers and services to you
  * For the purposes of our corporate governance

(Collectively referred to as “the Purposes”)  

 **Sharing of Your Personal Data  
**

 **  
**Your personal data may be disclosed to our parent company, vendor(s), contractor(s) and/or outsourcing company(ies) engaged by us for any of the above Purposes or any other purpose for which your personal data was to be disclosed at the time of its collection or any other purpose directly related to any of the above Purposes.  
  
Your personal data may be transferred and/or disclosed to any person(s) or institution(s) in or outside Malaysia including but not limited to the respective agents, authorised and appointed outsourcing agents for purpose of fulfilling our obligations to you in respect of the Purposes and all such other purposes that are related to the Purposes.  
  
We may also disclose your personal data to any Government authorities, agencies and/or any other regulatory body, to the extent that the Government or other authorities, agencies and/or any other regulatory body need to know, or as permitted by applicable laws and regulations.  

 **How We Protect Your Personal Data  
**

 **  
**Your personal information are dealt and/or handled by our authorized officers with strict confidentiality and are placed in our database(s), filing room(s) or store(s) where proper security measures are taken to avoid any unauthorized disclosure.  
  
Any personal information retained by us shall be destroyed and/or deleted in accordance with our retention policy applicable for us in the event such information is no longer required for the said reasons.  

 **Right to Access and Correct Your Personal Data**

You are entitled to obtain access to and request correction of the personal data provided to us by writing to us at [utp.pdp@petronas.com.my](mailto:utp.pdp@petronas.com.my)  
  
It is your obligation to ensure that all personal information submitted and retained are accurate, not misleading, updated and complete in all aspects.  
  
In accordance with the Personal Data Protection Act 2010:

  * UTP may charge a fee of up to RM10 (for personal data) and RM30 (for sensitive personal data) for processing your request for access to your personal data; and
  * UTP may refuse to comply with your request for access to or correction of your personal data

For the avoidance of doubt, UTP and/or its employees or authorised officers or agents will not be responsible for any personal information submitted by you that is inaccurate, misleading, incomplete and not updated.

You may at any time after the submission of your personal data to us, request for access, correction to your personal data and/or limit your data processing  
  
 **  
Retention of Your Personal Information  
** **  
**Your personal information will be retained by us only for the period necessary for the purposes of providing you with the services. If further retention period is required, we will obtain further consent from you, unless such extended retention is permitted by law.  

 **Changes to this Policy  
**

 **  
**If this privacy policy changes in any way, it will be updated on this page.  

 **Consent  
**

 **  
**You hereby are deemed to have given your consent to UTP to process the personal data that you have provided to us herein or through any other means for the Purposes and/or for any other purposes related to the Purpose.
